<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>outdoors on Evil Inc.</title>
    <link>http://sudosays.github.io/tags/outdoors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in outdoors on Evil Inc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 18:45:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sudosays.github.io/tags/outdoors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UltraTrail 2019</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/ultratrail-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 18:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/ultratrail-2019/</guid>
      <description>On the 30th of November this year I ran the 35km Ultra Trail in Cape Town.
At a glance, it took me a total of 8 hours 15 minutes to complete with an average pace of 13:53 min/km. According to my running watch, I burned 4583 calories with an average heart rate of 156bpm and a max heart rate of 186bpm over the entire 8+ hours.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;On the 30th of November this year I ran the 35km Ultra Trail in Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a glance, it took me a total of 8 hours 15 minutes to complete with an
average pace of 13:53 min/km. According to my running watch, I burned 4583
calories with an average heart rate of 156bpm and a max heart rate of 186bpm
over the entire 8+ hours. At a rough estimate, I drank 3.7 litres of water with
the heaviest consumption occurring between the 14km and 24km aid stations where
I completely drained my 1.5l race pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the official race timings and stats &lt;a href=&#34;https://utct.livetrail.run/coureur.php?rech=1572&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date this is my longest (time and distance) singular race event ever and I
thought I would share my experience and reflect on it. As such this post may
get a bit rambly and lengthy, but I have interspersed some photos of the event
to keep you interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_001.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_001.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;View of Cape Town from the Platteklip Gorge.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;View of Cape Town from the Platteklip Gorge.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to buy an entry in April this year and opted for the 35km over the
21km largely due to two factors: I wanted to push myself, and the 21km featured
a single climb over the saddle between Devil&amp;rsquo;s Peak and Table Mountain that
seemed quite dangerous to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, I ran my first half-marathon in Meiringspoort and I was confident I
could run 21km comfortably and wanted to push out past my comfort zone and
extend myself. Also, the 35km offered a traversal of Table Mountain and I
thought it was a great excuse to have an extended day on top of the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had my entry it came time for the training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_002.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_002.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;View of Platteklip Gorge during the ascent.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;View of Platteklip Gorge during the ascent.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year I saw a physio for some pretty advanced shin splints and
started a cross-training program with additional rehabilitation exercises.
Since the cross-training required cycling, I took up spinning and soon after
decided to commit to full triathlon training for an Olympic distance triathlon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the triathlon training to be super effective and enjoyable. It did
involve a lot more  cycling and swimming than running, but that was perfectly
fine since I was not supposed to be running so much in any case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The months flew by until roughly mid September when I got sick (likely from a
combination of overtraining, poor nutrition, and stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_003.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_003.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;View of Devil&amp;amp;rsquo;s Peak from the top of Table Mountain.&#34; height=&#34;450px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;View of Devil&amp;rsquo;s Peak from the top of Table Mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good two weeks lost and a whole bunch of fitness and muscle tone down
the drain, I managed to recover and restart training just in time for the
Meiringspoort half-marathon on the 12th of October. I surprised myself with a
finish time of 1:51:44 (only 4 minutes slower than last year&amp;rsquo;s 1:47:10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as race-day neared I became ever more encumbered by my work and
the priority of training dropped. As a result, I had not yet scouted the route,
broken in my trail shoes, done proper hill training, or run technical trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say I was nervous is an understatement. However, quitting and abandoning
this event was never really an option for me. Instead, I decided I would just
enjoy it as much as possible without worrying too much about setting a record
time or not. I set myself two core rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would run easy and slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would stop to take pictures and enjoy the scenes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back now, I am grateful I reframed it as I did. It really helped shift
my mentality to one of enjoyment in the undertaking and I would like to think,
contributed greatly to my overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_005.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_005.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Start of the descent down Nursery Ravine.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Start of the descent down Nursery Ravine.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on to actual the actual race. I was expecting a total time of roughly 10
hours, but I failed to take into account how congested the route would be. I
did indeed run when I was able to, but rather because the rest of the time I
would be hiking behind other racers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chokepoints of the route were Platteklip Gorge (and most of the beginning),
between Maclear&amp;rsquo;s Beacon and just before the aid station, and the Newland&amp;rsquo;s
Forest stairs. Once I had passed the stairs, the field opened up considerably,
but by that point my muscles were very heavily fatigued and made running
difficult to maintain for any considerable amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember at a point after the climb to the King&amp;rsquo;s Blockhouse I could only maintain
a run for at most 2-3 minutes before resorting to a fast walk. During most of
the race after Nursery Ravine, I remember repeating a little mantra to myself
that &amp;ldquo;run when you can, walk when you can&amp;rsquo;t run, but always stay moving
forward&amp;rdquo; over and over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_006.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_006.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;During the descent of Nursery Ravine.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;During the descent of Nursery Ravine.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that really stuck with me was how quickly time passed. I thought that
this will be an extended grind with gnashing of teeth and pain, but the first
14km or so passed by really quickly. I definitely experienced a sustained flow
state during the event with even the muscle pain not hampering my performance
too much. It could be that or it could have been the cramp block tablets I took
that I am sure saved my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself struggling to form a coherent narrative for this post and so
thought I would just rattle off a view highlights and notable events instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather on the day was as good as could be bargained for. Cool and cloudy
in the morning for the climb up Platteklip, and not windy for the homeward
stretch around Devil&amp;rsquo;s Peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the ascent of Platteklip, there was a bagpiper a little more than
halfway up. At the end of every tune, everyone would cheer and clap, and the
piper would take up another song. With the cloud rolling over the top of the
gorge it really lent a special air to the whole scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_008.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_008.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Climb to the King&amp;amp;rsquo;s Blockhouse.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Climb to the King&amp;rsquo;s Blockhouse.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views of Constantia and False Bay from Maclear&amp;rsquo;s Beacon were truly
breathtaking. At one point, I could see both sides of the Cape Penninsula before
me. It was just after this that I was able to help out a fellow racer by
offering some of my cramp block tablets. There was a prevailing spirit of
camaraderie and people were quick to help one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aid stations were excellently stocked with snacks and drinks. In
particular, at the aid station by UCT I managed to snag a Red Bull and some
jelly babies as well as seeing my supporters. After the 24km it took to get
there, seeing my loved ones there really made the last 10km bearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to finish strong with a run, and the macaroni and cheese afterwards
tasted like victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of aftermath, I was surprised at how quickly I managed to recover and
how I sustained no lasting damage. That being said, this event worked every
muscle in my legs. Trail running, it turns out, is a very comprehensive leg
exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All things considered, I am proud of what I accomplished with this event. I did
what I set out to do months ago, and even exceeded my own expectations. I am
still a bit uncertain if I would end up doing it next year, but I do know that
I will be doing more trail running regardless.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
