<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>long on Evil Inc.</title>
    <link>http://sudosays.github.io/tags/long/</link>
    <description>Recent content in long on Evil Inc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:33:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sudosays.github.io/tags/long/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deathrolling for Gold</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/deathrolling-for-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:33:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/deathrolling-for-gold/</guid>
      <description>Money is the root of all evil. Our evil endeavors can only succeed if we are well funded. More so, our funds should come from either an untraceable or laundered source. While cryptocurrency is a viable payment method that seems reasonably untraceable, let us not stake our funds on a somewhat volatile market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UltraTrail 2019</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/ultratrail-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 18:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/ultratrail-2019/</guid>
      <description>On the 30th of November this year I ran the 35km Ultra Trail in Cape Town.
At a glance, it took me a total of 8 hours 15 minutes to complete with an average pace of 13:53 min/km. According to my running watch, I burned 4583 calories with an average heart rate of 156bpm and a max heart rate of 186bpm over the entire 8+ hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog #4: Tempo</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-4-tempo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 10:29:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-4-tempo/</guid>
      <description>First of all, let me apologise in advance. This is going to be a somewhat lengthy one. I had gotten caught up in the development and rounding out of the features, and neglected to report on the progress. However, as it currently stands, the app is in a functional state. So much so that I have been using it consistently in my daily life already, despite some missing features that make it a bit frustrating to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog #3: Tempo</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-3-tempo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 11:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-3-tempo/</guid>
      <description>At the end of the previous devlog  I used AsyncTasks to implement the very basic “Add Task” functionality. Next I set to work getting the other most important feature working: the “flow mode”. The flow mode is where the Pomodorro technique I discussed in the very first devlog is applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog #2: Tempo</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-2-tempo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 09:55:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-2-tempo/</guid>
      <description>At this stage the first major functionality of the app has been implemented.
With this devlog I cover how I added data persistence of the tasks as well as the “Add Task” functionality. I used the Room library that comes as part of Android Jetpack for expediency, but nonetheless I had some stumbling blocks and learning points along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog #1: Tempo</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-1-tempo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 20:25:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-1-tempo/</guid>
      <description>In my last devlog for my productivity app Tempo, I discussed how I had created a CustomView for my Task object, how I would add them directly to my main ConstraintLayout, and how I fixed the layout by using LayoutParams.
In this post, I set out thinking how I was going to discuss implementing the “Add Task” functionality and managing the list of tasks in the MainActivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog: Tempo</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-tempo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 13:25:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-tempo/</guid>
      <description>As a supervillain, I would like to ensure that my minions and peons are working at maximum efficiency. The following post (and probably series) describes my journey in creating a tool that will help them stay productive.
This leads me to a question: What tomatoes, egg timers, and university have in common?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
