<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>update on Evil Inc.</title>
    <link>http://sudosays.github.io/tags/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in update on Evil Inc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:59:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sudosays.github.io/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hindsight 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:59:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</guid>
      <description>What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost deferred itself.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year
posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year
I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose
things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost
deferred itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the 5 goals I set, 2 have been completed entirely: contribute to an open
source initiative, and donate blood. These were binary in nature, either I did
them or did not. For the others (yoga/flexibility, writing, and personal
project) it was less clear cut. These goals required continuous and even
effort. As the posts on this blog make clear, the effort was continuous, but
sporadic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did in fact write more, but perhaps it was off target for what I had
envisioned. I also became more flexible, for a while. Finally, I worked on, but
did not complete a personal project. Considering the tumultuous year, I am not
overly disappointed. I made inroads into the goals I had set, and for others I
achieved them. That is enough for me and enough about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year will definitely be one for the history books. Wracked by a pandemic,
society was torn apart and recombined. As the virus swept around the globe,
countries went into various stages of lockdown. South Africa, for one went into
a total lock down for a long time before a phased return to a new normal. Even
now, 2021 is gearing up for another year of pandemic protocols and social
upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout all of this, we have been given the display of the best of humanity
and the worst of humanity. Though separated through social distancing, we
connected through the internet. We drew closer together to immediate family. We
took, hopefully, a step back and noted the things we missed, and those we could
probably live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, the economic and social devastation has not even begun to rear its
ugly head. The bell has tolled ceaselessly and will continue to do so. By all
indications, this virus is here to stay for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the metaphorical night will grow ever darker over the next few years, but
hopefully we can remain huddled around a flicker of light, together.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, August 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-august-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 15:32:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-august-2020/</guid>
      <description>Yet again it is time for another update. The past month I have been incredibly busy. I have recently taken up a lecturing position for a Java course at a local university. While entirely online/remote, the work is quite time consuming if not overly difficult. I have found it interesting to develop an effective workflow and schedule, and to find the relevant tools that allow me to do so.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;Yet again it is time for another update. The past month I have been incredibly
busy. I have recently taken up a lecturing position for a Java course at a
local university. While entirely online/remote, the work is quite time
consuming if not overly difficult. I have found it interesting to develop an
effective workflow and schedule, and to find the relevant tools that allow me
to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested, my current &amp;ldquo;stack&amp;rdquo;/workflow for lectures is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing all slides and notes in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiling to Beamer slides with &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org/&#34;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording of lecture videos material with &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/&#34;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://junit.org/junit5/&#34;&gt;JUnit 5&lt;/a&gt; for automated assignment marking and testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sakailms.org/&#34;&gt;Sakai&lt;/a&gt; for student interaction and assessments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also found myself using &lt;a href=&#34;https://taskwarrior.org/&#34;&gt;Taskwarrior&lt;/a&gt; quite a
bit, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I really like it. Something about the usage seems to
rub at me. For a while I was considering adding Taskwarrior support to Tempo,
but I will probably hold off for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I am currently preparing a paper for the SACAIR conference as
part of my MSc work. It is proving an intense process, but I expected it would
be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what free time I have left, I find myself surfing, playing chess, and
playing Bloodborne (although not that often).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself itching to work on Tempo as well as a plethora of other personal
project ideas (mostly in Go). For now though, they will have to remain on the
backburner. Until the next update, keep well in these interesting times.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, July 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:41:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>It is time again for me to fill you in with another status update. I have been incredibly busy with my academics this past while which has left little time for side-projects (despite how much I would like to work on them). What little time I have free I have been surfing, meditating, doing yoga, and sleeping to try and recover and recoup.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;It is time again for me to fill you in with another status update. I have been
incredibly busy with my academics this past while which has left little time
for side-projects (despite how much I would like to work on them). What little
time I have free I have been surfing, meditating, doing yoga, and sleeping to
try and recover and recoup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of what my workload looks like I mapped it with
Matplotlib+Numpy using &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/32485907/matplotlib-and-numpy-create-a-calendar-heatmap&#34;&gt;Joe
Kinton&amp;rsquo;s
answer&lt;/a&gt;
on Stack Overflow as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/workload_heatmap.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/workload_heatmap.png&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My productivity app Tempo has seen some slight changes as I have tinkered away
at it and I have been using it relentlessly to keep myself focused and maintain
my work momentum. A lot has been changed and improved since the last devlog and
frankly another one is long overdue. Yet again, I have found that using my app
constantly really brings to light any issues or quirks that annoy me which has
been a great way to know what things I need to change or polish first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have been writing more Go in my spare time &amp;mdash; mostly with toy
projects &amp;mdash; and I have to say that I am quickly falling in love with it. I had
expected my self to prefer Rust, but somehow Go pleasantly surprised me with
the dev tools. In some way I feel that Go has been a lot easier for me to grok
than Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That does not mean that I have abandoned learning Rust, but rather
that I have shelved it for now in favour of focusing on mastering Go. I am
still especially interested in adding Rust to my repertoire especially since
there is talk of including &lt;a href=&#34;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CAKwvOdmuYc8rW_H4aQG4DsJzho=F+djd68fp7mzmBp3-wY--Uw@mail.gmail.com/T/#u&#34;&gt;in-tree Rust
support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, June 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 17:34:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>This post is inspired by the status updates of Drew DeVault (who remains a large inspiration for keeping this blog as a whole). This entry is a bit late, but better than never. In future I think I will also try to update at the middle of each month. This is also a chance to add updates from my life that do not warrant a full post here or may seem unrelated to the spirit of this blog.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by the status updates of Drew DeVault (who remains a
large inspiration for keeping this blog as a whole). This entry is a bit late,
but better than never. In future I think I will also try to update at the
middle of each month. This is also a chance to add updates from my life that do
not warrant a full post here or may seem unrelated to the spirit of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last post to this blog was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/blog/be-static-to-go-faster/&#34;&gt;Be Static To Go Faster&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which dates back to the 25th of February
this year. In the intervening months, many, many things have happened. I have
been working towards the completion of my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree, drafted a whole
bunch of posts only to abandon them later. These last few months of quarantine
and lockdown have been incredibly turbulent and the time slipped by in the
blink of an eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not have much else to report as of now. There are a few things in the
works especially with respect to Tempo and other projects. However, I will be
focusing mainly on my degree for the next while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, study hard and, stay evil.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
