<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>growth on Evil Inc.</title>
    <link>http://sudosays.github.io/tags/growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in growth on Evil Inc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 15:39:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sudosays.github.io/tags/growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 The Diet</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2021-the-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 15:39:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2021-the-diet/</guid>
      <description>Admittedly, the third week in January is a bit late to post my New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution, but better late than never.
Last year, I had a focus on growth with a community slant to it. I donated blood, contributed to an open source project and tried to add to myself.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, the third week in January is a bit late to post my New Year&amp;rsquo;s
Resolution, but better late than never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I had a focus on growth with a community slant to it. I donated
blood, contributed to an open source project and tried to add to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, my central goal is to &amp;ldquo;diet&amp;rdquo;: physically, spiritually, and
digitally. There is a common conception of a diet as a restriction and
reduction of intake, foregoing the things we believe are enjoyable. It leaves
the idea of a diet as a bleak and joyless process that ultimately will end and
we may return to our old habits of eating cake or whatever vice we enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to diet in the holistic sense of the word: to not just reduce/stop
consuming things deemed unhealthy, but to replace them with things that nourish
me. Furthermore, while also physical, I aim to undergo a digital diet as well.
The two overlap on the concept of a &amp;ldquo;dopamine diet&amp;rdquo;, a restriction of excess
neurochemical stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-physical-diet&#34;&gt;The Physical Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is somewhat straightforward: I currently weigh ~82kgs and I would like
that to be under 76kgs. This would shift my BMI from overweight to normal
weight. However, while achieving this, I would like to make it a sustainable
thing and that requires a lifestyle change including diet and exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite sports are surfing, running, and rock climbing. However, due to
the lockdown restrictions and an injury, I am unable to surf or run, which
leaves only climbing. To balance this, I will be adding yoga as a regular
fixture of my routine. The first two weeks of this year, I did yoga almost
every day, and I could definitely feel the benefit it had on not only my
physical well-being, but also helped reduce my stress levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body and the mind are connected. Therefore, an important part of the
physical diet is a practise of managing the psychosomatic response to stress.
Through meditation, yoga, and other mentally restorative practices I hope to
reduce my stress levels. Studies suggest that stress enhances the craving and
increases risk of relapse in alcoholics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for nutrition, I am cutting out all snack and junk foods. The rule is, if it
comes in a sweet packet, or from a fast food restaurant: it is not allowed.
Regular restaurants are a grey area, and so the general rule of thumb is to
take the healthier of the menu options. This is not an absolute rule so that I
can hopefully avoid a self-defeating guilt/binge cycle. The focus is on
rewarding positive change and not punishing failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-digital-diet&#34;&gt;The Digital Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other aspect I would like to tackle is my consumption of digital media.
Whether it be videos, games, social media, or news, I would like to reduce the
amount of digital content I consume. These things are designed to be rewarding,
and some even highly optimised to promote their use/consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest example for me is video games. By design, they reward the player for
completing certain tasks in the game. Furthermore, it is easy to feel a sense
of mastery, accomplishment, or progress especially in games such as Factorio.
For video games, this is an overt part of the design, but for other things such
as social media it is more difficult to spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These systems are designed to be rewarding, to stimulate the release of
dopamine which is linked to our reward centers. The idea is to hijack the
reward stimulus and &amp;ldquo;farm&amp;rdquo; a user for dopamine, increasing engagement. The
problems I have with this is that: a) it can easily become addictive, and b)
overstimulation of the brain can make other tasks feel less rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I realised during lockdown last year, and what I hope to achieve this year
is that I enjoy tackling problems. I thrive when struggling against really
difficult challenges and finding a creative solution for it. Unfortunately, if
my reward centers are already overstimulated, I find it difficult to sink my
teeth into a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therfore, the digital/dopamine diet. Replacing the easy &amp;ldquo;mental junk food&amp;rdquo;
activities with more difficult, but more rewarding activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to replace my current diet of digital entertainment with writing,
reading, meditation, chess, and creative activities such as drawing or
programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-resolution&#34;&gt;The Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above has been very theoretical and wishy washy. The concrete
resolution is as follows (and as always follows the SMART principle):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to lose 6kgs before July 2021 and maintain it until 31 December
2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to reduce my digital consumption to 1 movie or 2 tv episodes
and no more than 1 hour of video games per week by July 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to stop consuming any social media and limit the time spent
surfing the internet to 30 minutes per day by the end of the year (31
December 2021).
internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be keeping track of these privately throughout the year and will report
back further.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindsight 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:59:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</guid>
      <description>What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost deferred itself.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year
posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year
I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose
things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost
deferred itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the 5 goals I set, 2 have been completed entirely: contribute to an open
source initiative, and donate blood. These were binary in nature, either I did
them or did not. For the others (yoga/flexibility, writing, and personal
project) it was less clear cut. These goals required continuous and even
effort. As the posts on this blog make clear, the effort was continuous, but
sporadic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did in fact write more, but perhaps it was off target for what I had
envisioned. I also became more flexible, for a while. Finally, I worked on, but
did not complete a personal project. Considering the tumultuous year, I am not
overly disappointed. I made inroads into the goals I had set, and for others I
achieved them. That is enough for me and enough about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year will definitely be one for the history books. Wracked by a pandemic,
society was torn apart and recombined. As the virus swept around the globe,
countries went into various stages of lockdown. South Africa, for one went into
a total lock down for a long time before a phased return to a new normal. Even
now, 2021 is gearing up for another year of pandemic protocols and social
upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout all of this, we have been given the display of the best of humanity
and the worst of humanity. Though separated through social distancing, we
connected through the internet. We drew closer together to immediate family. We
took, hopefully, a step back and noted the things we missed, and those we could
probably live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, the economic and social devastation has not even begun to rear its
ugly head. The bell has tolled ceaselessly and will continue to do so. By all
indications, this virus is here to stay for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the metaphorical night will grow ever darker over the next few years, but
hopefully we can remain huddled around a flicker of light, together.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commitunism</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/commitunism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 15:20:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/commitunism/</guid>
      <description>In my 2020 vision, I mentioned that this year I wanted to contribute to an open source project and I am happy to announce that my first ever pull request was merged. This post mainly concerns my experience of the contribution process and my thoughts throughout rather than an in depth technical report.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2020-vision/&#34;&gt;2020 vision&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that this year I wanted to contribute to an
open source project and I am happy to announce that my first ever pull
request was &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sylabs/singularity/commit/efeb67deb1519b792d021e6c305069701c5fe9a6&#34;&gt;merged&lt;/a&gt;.
This post mainly concerns my experience of the contribution process and my
thoughts throughout rather than an in depth technical report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I embarked on this journey I had a few criteria that I was looking for in
my contribution. Specifically, I wanted to contribute something meaningful to
both me and others which meant that I wanted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to contribute to a project I use or found interesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to add value to others&#39; experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to add value to the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those parameters I went through the Github issues of projects I liked and
checked the &amp;ldquo;good first issue&amp;rdquo; labels until I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sylabs/singularity/issues/3502&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;
in the repository for Singularity (a containerisation tool for high performance
computing on Linux). The issue stood out to me, because I had also stumbled
into the same headache as the author and it seemed to me to be a very
achievable thing to fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I was tempted to comment on the issue that I could look into it, but
a teacher of mine once told me, &amp;ldquo;talk is cheap&amp;rdquo;, and so I decided to instead
produce a solution first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;doing-my-homework&#34;&gt;Doing My Homework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I had a vague idea of what the process was for contributing to
open source projects, I also know that each project might have a subtly
different workflow for contributions. As a result, I made sure to read the
contribution guidelines for the project, and forked the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do was to ensure that I was able to actually compile the
project from source, which meant understanding the build system and
dependencies. Luckily, working with lots of build systems (and even writing my
own makefiles) meant that it went smoothly and soon I had a workflow figured
out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-problem&#34;&gt;Finding the Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I had reached the limit of my comfort zone. The project is
written in Go which I had very little experience with having only completed
the Tour of Go previously. Furthermore, I was not at all familiar with the
codebase and so my first issue was finding where the problem could actually be
solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I am a bit lazy and instead of reading through each and every file
to find something I ended up using a recursive &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; search to find the
specific occurrence of the sanity check prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ grep -r &amp;quot;Build target already exists&amp;quot;

cmd/internal/cli/build.go: question := &amp;quot;Build target already exists. Do you want to overwrite? [N/y] &amp;quot;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I dove into the &lt;code&gt;build.go&lt;/code&gt; file and found the line where the prompt was
being served, but if I was really clever I would have added the &lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; option to
&lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; which would spit out the line number as well as the file it was in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ grep -rn &amp;quot;Build target already exists&amp;quot;

cmd/internal/cli/build.go:268: question := &amp;quot;Build target already exists. Do you want to overwrite? [N/y] &amp;quot;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-solve&#34;&gt;Initial Solve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought about solving this was to check if the build target file had
the &lt;code&gt;.def&lt;/code&gt; extension that denotes it as a build file. However, there were two
big issues with this approach: it depended on the name of the file rather than
the content, it required introducing the &lt;code&gt;os&lt;/code&gt; package to the file which I
thought was unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through the file for tools I could use I came across the following
method &lt;code&gt;parser.IsValidDefinition(path string)&lt;/code&gt; which would judge a build target
file on its content rather than its name. Furthermore, it incorporated the
internally built tools to check definition files. This lead me to the following
diff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-diff&#34; data-lang=&#34;diff&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000080;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;diff --git a/cmd/internal/cli/build.go b/cmd/internal/cli/build.go
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000080;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;index fe02643162..558a7a2bfc 100644
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000080;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a40000&#34;&gt;--- a/cmd/internal/cli/build.go
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a40000&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+++ b/cmd/internal/cli/build.go
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#800080;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;@@ -265,7 +265,17 @@ func checkBuildTarget(path string) error {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#800080;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; 			return fmt.Errorf(&amp;#34;only sandbox update is supported: %s is not a directory&amp;#34;, path)
 		}
 		if !buildArgs.update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !forceOverwrite {
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a40000&#34;&gt;-			question := &amp;#34;Build target already exists. Do you want to overwrite? [N/y] &amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a40000&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+			var question string
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+			isDefFile, _ := parser.IsValidDefinition(path)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+			if isDefFile {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+				question = &amp;#34;Build target is a valid definition file that will be overwritten. Do you still want to overwrite? [N/y]&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+			} else {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+				question = &amp;#34;Build target already exists. Do you want to overwrite? [N/y] &amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+			}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;+
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#00a000&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; 			input, err := interactive.AskYNQuestion(&amp;#34;n&amp;#34;, question)
 			if err != nil {
 				return fmt.Errorf(&amp;#34;while reading the input: %s&amp;#34;, err)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;What followed was a bit strange for me. I pushed the new commit/branch to my
fork with the commit message &amp;ldquo;Add build command sanity check to close #3502&amp;rdquo;
with &amp;ldquo;#3502&amp;rdquo; being the reference to the issue in the main repo. I did not
expect this to immediately reflect on the issue in the main upstream
repository. So when I amended my commit because I forgot to ensure all the test
cases, and builds passed, it also reflected multiple commits on the main issue
conversation. Although unexpected, this is very useful for connecting commits
to issues automagically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excited and thrilled, I opened a pull request and waited for a review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-loop&#34;&gt;Feedback Loop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pull review process was also a novel experience for me. Initially I was
worried that my changes would be outright rejected, and my PR tanked. Instead,
there was a back and forth discussion between myself and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dctrud&#34;&gt;David
Trudgian&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; a maintainer for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation about how to address the problem resulted &amp;mdash; at least in my
view &amp;mdash; in a solution that was greater than something I could have achieved by
myself. I would incorporate suggested changes and neaten up my code which ended
up in a total of three commits for the pull request. The review process felt
very welcoming and collaborative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;victory&#34;&gt;Victory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all suggestions incorporated, continuous integration and build tests
passed, my PR finally passed review and was merged into the master branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I believe that the contribution I made was definitely beneficial to
future users of the software, I definitely walked away from this experience
with a lot more insight. I experienced the power of the review process, and
that contributing to open source is not only achievable, but exciting and
enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely plan on making more contributions to Singularity in the future,
although I suspect not all of them will warrant a full blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - The Organised Mind</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/book-review-the-organised-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:09:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/book-review-the-organised-mind/</guid>
      <description>Last night I finally managed to finish Daniel Levitin&amp;rsquo;s The Organised Mind and while that phrasing might make it sound like this book was a drag, it was the exact opposite. It is so densely packed with revelation after revelation, that to read it in a rush is to do yourself an injustice.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;Last night I finally managed to finish Daniel Levitin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Organised Mind&lt;/em&gt;
and while that phrasing might make it sound like this book was a drag, it was
the exact opposite.  It is so densely packed with revelation after revelation,
that to read it in a rush is to do yourself an injustice. I found that I had to
break up the book into smaller manageable pieces and let them digest for a
while before I could go on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Organised Mind&lt;/em&gt; is a thorough and exacting investigation into how our
relationship with information has evolved, and how we can actively pursue
mental habits that will empower us to become more effective in the modern age.
Levitin demonstrates his mastery over the subject by how simply and easily he
is able to drift through a multitude of disciplines to bring to life a
compelling narrative. While some writing is great for the ideas it brings
forth, and some writing is great for the text itself, &lt;em&gt;The Organised Mind&lt;/em&gt;
achieves both in what I would hope will become a classic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do not wish to ruin the enjoyment of the future reader of this work, I
do want to touch on some of the concepts that stuck with me, even if just
briefly. The primary idea that had the greatest impact on me was &lt;em&gt;cognitive
offloading&lt;/em&gt;: how we have developed tools to externalise information and
thought processes so as to free up our brains to be able to devote more power
to the thoughts that matter to us. It is a way to unclutter the brain and
attention so that we may achieve focus and hopefully more effective cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second concept that stuck with me was that of the &lt;em&gt;attentional filtering&lt;/em&gt;
to conserve our attentional bandwidth. We have a very limited attention span,
and rely largely on heuristics to filter out the unnecessary things. This means
that if we are doing too many things at once, our brains start to drop memories
and attention for things it deems low priority. This is how we can start to
forget where we left something or what we were doing. Attention is a limited
resource and susceptible to a buffer overflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend this book to anyone, and especially to those
interested in building a stronger, working relationship with information and
their mind.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Vision</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2020-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 19:56:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2020-vision/</guid>
      <description>While normally I would keep my New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions to myself, blogging more is one of them. If I could control how this year will turn out for me I would summarise it in one word: growth. My aim this year is to extend myself in as many aspects as I can while ensuring lasting impact.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;While normally I would keep my New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions to myself, blogging more
is one of them. If I could control how this year will turn out for me I would
summarise it in one word: growth. My aim this year is to extend myself in as
many aspects as I can while ensuring lasting impact. As such, I have narrowed
it down to five resolutions or goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all of these conform to the S.M.A.R.T principle of goal setting, but I
don&amp;rsquo;t think resolutions have to be such hard goals. Regardless, they are as
follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to an open source initiative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donate blood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become more flexible (with yoga)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write more (in this blog and elsewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete a personal project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had trouble deciding on which ones exactly to include here, but I think these
represent things that I had always told myself I would get around to at some
point. They represent deferred, delayed, and abandoned ideas/goals that I think
make them prime candidates for this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the growth I seek is commitment: building on things that I believe
will make me a better, more dedicated person while contributing to my community
(online or otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these, I have included a brief on how I imagined they would be
accomplished or how I envisioned them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source initiatives to contribute to include Wikipedia, and Rust-based
projects for helping me learn the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donating blood is pretty self-explanatory, I am ashamed to say I have never
really done it before and it has always been a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming more flexible is a physical challenge I set myself since I recovered
from my advanced shin splints. Lack of flexibility in my hamstrings was one of
the leading factors to the development of what could have been a chronic
injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing more involves building out this blog and taking the initiative to share
my knowledge and personal discoveries with others. Blogs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://drewdevault.com/&#34;&gt;Drew
DeVault&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; are a big source of inspiration for this
one. I also have many other writing projects that have simply never been a
priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I want to see a personal project through to completion. My project
graveyard stretches across the horizon while my harvest remains empty. I hope
to start adding to the archive and showcase of this blog at least one project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to challenge you &amp;mdash; dear reader &amp;mdash; to anything this year it would
be this: find something you have always deferred and just start the work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
