<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools on Evil Inc.</title>
    <link>http://sudosays.github.io/categories/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools on Evil Inc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 16:21:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sudosays.github.io/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Master&#39;s Tools</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/the-masters-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 16:21:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/the-masters-tools/</guid>
      <description>In order to build an evil empire, one must be able to build. To build things that are robust and long lasting requires the carefully honed skill of the master. Mastery is required if one is to become an effective supervillain. It is important to develop a deep knowledge and mastery over the tools required for one&amp;rsquo;s schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog: Pneuma</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-pneuma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 07:40:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/devlog-pneuma/</guid>
      <description>Producing propaganda takes priority for prospective pernicious persons. As a supervillian, it is important to be able to reach your audience and propagate your ideas. This blog is my version of that and for the last while I have been using the static site generator Hugo after migrating from Wordpress (see this post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pneuma</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/projects/pneuma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 09:22:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/projects/pneuma/</guid>
      <description>Pneuma (stylised as pneuma) is an interactive terminal frontend for managing a Hugo blog. As with Tempo, I built it for myself with the features I would like in it.
The aim of the project is to provide a slick, minimal frontend for managing posts in a Hugo blog including the ability to edit and create new posts, as well as publish drafts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Static to Go Faster</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/be-static-to-go-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 16:50:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/be-static-to-go-faster/</guid>
      <description>One of the important factors in being a supervillain is that you need to be able to get your word out there. This can be for multiple reasons such as recruiting henchmen, drawing the ire of heroes, networking with other supervillains, and the list goes on. For an incipient supervillain such as myself, this comes in the form of my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commitunism</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/commitunism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 15:20:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/commitunism/</guid>
      <description>In my 2020 vision, I mentioned that this year I wanted to contribute to an open source project and I am happy to announce that my first ever pull request was merged. This post mainly concerns my experience of the contribution process and my thoughts throughout rather than an in depth technical report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Leadership Revisited</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/vim-leadership-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:03:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/vim-leadership-revisited/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I wrote about my discovery of using the leader key in vim (you can read that here). Now, after using it for a while I would like to revisit it and share my experiences and what I have learned.
First of all, do not use the spacebar for your leader key, and second of all beware your timeouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a Leader in Vim</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/being-a-leader-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 13:42:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/being-a-leader-in-vim/</guid>
      <description>As far as using IDEs go, I wouldn’t say I’ve been around the block, but I’ve seen my fair share. It was only when I started running Arch Linux that I first switched to vim. At this point you might be expecting me to sing vim’s praises and how every developer worth their salt should be using it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
