<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>general on Evil Inc.</title>
    <link>http://sudosays.github.io/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in general on Evil Inc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 15:39:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sudosays.github.io/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 The Diet</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2021-the-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 15:39:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2021-the-diet/</guid>
      <description>Admittedly, the third week in January is a bit late to post my New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution, but better late than never.
Last year, I had a focus on growth with a community slant to it. I donated blood, contributed to an open source project and tried to add to myself.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, the third week in January is a bit late to post my New Year&amp;rsquo;s
Resolution, but better late than never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I had a focus on growth with a community slant to it. I donated
blood, contributed to an open source project and tried to add to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, my central goal is to &amp;ldquo;diet&amp;rdquo;: physically, spiritually, and
digitally. There is a common conception of a diet as a restriction and
reduction of intake, foregoing the things we believe are enjoyable. It leaves
the idea of a diet as a bleak and joyless process that ultimately will end and
we may return to our old habits of eating cake or whatever vice we enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to diet in the holistic sense of the word: to not just reduce/stop
consuming things deemed unhealthy, but to replace them with things that nourish
me. Furthermore, while also physical, I aim to undergo a digital diet as well.
The two overlap on the concept of a &amp;ldquo;dopamine diet&amp;rdquo;, a restriction of excess
neurochemical stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-physical-diet&#34;&gt;The Physical Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is somewhat straightforward: I currently weigh ~82kgs and I would like
that to be under 76kgs. This would shift my BMI from overweight to normal
weight. However, while achieving this, I would like to make it a sustainable
thing and that requires a lifestyle change including diet and exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite sports are surfing, running, and rock climbing. However, due to
the lockdown restrictions and an injury, I am unable to surf or run, which
leaves only climbing. To balance this, I will be adding yoga as a regular
fixture of my routine. The first two weeks of this year, I did yoga almost
every day, and I could definitely feel the benefit it had on not only my
physical well-being, but also helped reduce my stress levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body and the mind are connected. Therefore, an important part of the
physical diet is a practise of managing the psychosomatic response to stress.
Through meditation, yoga, and other mentally restorative practices I hope to
reduce my stress levels. Studies suggest that stress enhances the craving and
increases risk of relapse in alcoholics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for nutrition, I am cutting out all snack and junk foods. The rule is, if it
comes in a sweet packet, or from a fast food restaurant: it is not allowed.
Regular restaurants are a grey area, and so the general rule of thumb is to
take the healthier of the menu options. This is not an absolute rule so that I
can hopefully avoid a self-defeating guilt/binge cycle. The focus is on
rewarding positive change and not punishing failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-digital-diet&#34;&gt;The Digital Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other aspect I would like to tackle is my consumption of digital media.
Whether it be videos, games, social media, or news, I would like to reduce the
amount of digital content I consume. These things are designed to be rewarding,
and some even highly optimised to promote their use/consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest example for me is video games. By design, they reward the player for
completing certain tasks in the game. Furthermore, it is easy to feel a sense
of mastery, accomplishment, or progress especially in games such as Factorio.
For video games, this is an overt part of the design, but for other things such
as social media it is more difficult to spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These systems are designed to be rewarding, to stimulate the release of
dopamine which is linked to our reward centers. The idea is to hijack the
reward stimulus and &amp;ldquo;farm&amp;rdquo; a user for dopamine, increasing engagement. The
problems I have with this is that: a) it can easily become addictive, and b)
overstimulation of the brain can make other tasks feel less rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I realised during lockdown last year, and what I hope to achieve this year
is that I enjoy tackling problems. I thrive when struggling against really
difficult challenges and finding a creative solution for it. Unfortunately, if
my reward centers are already overstimulated, I find it difficult to sink my
teeth into a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therfore, the digital/dopamine diet. Replacing the easy &amp;ldquo;mental junk food&amp;rdquo;
activities with more difficult, but more rewarding activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to replace my current diet of digital entertainment with writing,
reading, meditation, chess, and creative activities such as drawing or
programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-resolution&#34;&gt;The Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above has been very theoretical and wishy washy. The concrete
resolution is as follows (and as always follows the SMART principle):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to lose 6kgs before July 2021 and maintain it until 31 December
2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to reduce my digital consumption to 1 movie or 2 tv episodes
and no more than 1 hour of video games per week by July 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to stop consuming any social media and limit the time spent
surfing the internet to 30 minutes per day by the end of the year (31
December 2021).
internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be keeping track of these privately throughout the year and will report
back further.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindsight 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:59:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</guid>
      <description>What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost deferred itself.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year
posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year
I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose
things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost
deferred itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the 5 goals I set, 2 have been completed entirely: contribute to an open
source initiative, and donate blood. These were binary in nature, either I did
them or did not. For the others (yoga/flexibility, writing, and personal
project) it was less clear cut. These goals required continuous and even
effort. As the posts on this blog make clear, the effort was continuous, but
sporadic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did in fact write more, but perhaps it was off target for what I had
envisioned. I also became more flexible, for a while. Finally, I worked on, but
did not complete a personal project. Considering the tumultuous year, I am not
overly disappointed. I made inroads into the goals I had set, and for others I
achieved them. That is enough for me and enough about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year will definitely be one for the history books. Wracked by a pandemic,
society was torn apart and recombined. As the virus swept around the globe,
countries went into various stages of lockdown. South Africa, for one went into
a total lock down for a long time before a phased return to a new normal. Even
now, 2021 is gearing up for another year of pandemic protocols and social
upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout all of this, we have been given the display of the best of humanity
and the worst of humanity. Though separated through social distancing, we
connected through the internet. We drew closer together to immediate family. We
took, hopefully, a step back and noted the things we missed, and those we could
probably live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, the economic and social devastation has not even begun to rear its
ugly head. The bell has tolled ceaselessly and will continue to do so. By all
indications, this virus is here to stay for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the metaphorical night will grow ever darker over the next few years, but
hopefully we can remain huddled around a flicker of light, together.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, August 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-august-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 15:32:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-august-2020/</guid>
      <description>Yet again it is time for another update. The past month I have been incredibly busy. I have recently taken up a lecturing position for a Java course at a local university. While entirely online/remote, the work is quite time consuming if not overly difficult. I have found it interesting to develop an effective workflow and schedule, and to find the relevant tools that allow me to do so.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;Yet again it is time for another update. The past month I have been incredibly
busy. I have recently taken up a lecturing position for a Java course at a
local university. While entirely online/remote, the work is quite time
consuming if not overly difficult. I have found it interesting to develop an
effective workflow and schedule, and to find the relevant tools that allow me
to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested, my current &amp;ldquo;stack&amp;rdquo;/workflow for lectures is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing all slides and notes in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiling to Beamer slides with &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org/&#34;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording of lecture videos material with &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/&#34;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://junit.org/junit5/&#34;&gt;JUnit 5&lt;/a&gt; for automated assignment marking and testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sakailms.org/&#34;&gt;Sakai&lt;/a&gt; for student interaction and assessments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also found myself using &lt;a href=&#34;https://taskwarrior.org/&#34;&gt;Taskwarrior&lt;/a&gt; quite a
bit, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I really like it. Something about the usage seems to
rub at me. For a while I was considering adding Taskwarrior support to Tempo,
but I will probably hold off for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I am currently preparing a paper for the SACAIR conference as
part of my MSc work. It is proving an intense process, but I expected it would
be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what free time I have left, I find myself surfing, playing chess, and
playing Bloodborne (although not that often).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself itching to work on Tempo as well as a plethora of other personal
project ideas (mostly in Go). For now though, they will have to remain on the
backburner. Until the next update, keep well in these interesting times.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, July 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:41:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>It is time again for me to fill you in with another status update. I have been incredibly busy with my academics this past while which has left little time for side-projects (despite how much I would like to work on them). What little time I have free I have been surfing, meditating, doing yoga, and sleeping to try and recover and recoup.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;It is time again for me to fill you in with another status update. I have been
incredibly busy with my academics this past while which has left little time
for side-projects (despite how much I would like to work on them). What little
time I have free I have been surfing, meditating, doing yoga, and sleeping to
try and recover and recoup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of what my workload looks like I mapped it with
Matplotlib+Numpy using &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/32485907/matplotlib-and-numpy-create-a-calendar-heatmap&#34;&gt;Joe
Kinton&amp;rsquo;s
answer&lt;/a&gt;
on Stack Overflow as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/workload_heatmap.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/workload_heatmap.png&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My productivity app Tempo has seen some slight changes as I have tinkered away
at it and I have been using it relentlessly to keep myself focused and maintain
my work momentum. A lot has been changed and improved since the last devlog and
frankly another one is long overdue. Yet again, I have found that using my app
constantly really brings to light any issues or quirks that annoy me which has
been a great way to know what things I need to change or polish first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have been writing more Go in my spare time &amp;mdash; mostly with toy
projects &amp;mdash; and I have to say that I am quickly falling in love with it. I had
expected my self to prefer Rust, but somehow Go pleasantly surprised me with
the dev tools. In some way I feel that Go has been a lot easier for me to grok
than Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That does not mean that I have abandoned learning Rust, but rather
that I have shelved it for now in favour of focusing on mastering Go. I am
still especially interested in adding Rust to my repertoire especially since
there is talk of including &lt;a href=&#34;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CAKwvOdmuYc8rW_H4aQG4DsJzho=F+djd68fp7mzmBp3-wY--Uw@mail.gmail.com/T/#u&#34;&gt;in-tree Rust
support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, June 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 17:34:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>This post is inspired by the status updates of Drew DeVault (who remains a large inspiration for keeping this blog as a whole). This entry is a bit late, but better than never. In future I think I will also try to update at the middle of each month. This is also a chance to add updates from my life that do not warrant a full post here or may seem unrelated to the spirit of this blog.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by the status updates of Drew DeVault (who remains a
large inspiration for keeping this blog as a whole). This entry is a bit late,
but better than never. In future I think I will also try to update at the
middle of each month. This is also a chance to add updates from my life that do
not warrant a full post here or may seem unrelated to the spirit of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last post to this blog was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/blog/be-static-to-go-faster/&#34;&gt;Be Static To Go Faster&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which dates back to the 25th of February
this year. In the intervening months, many, many things have happened. I have
been working towards the completion of my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree, drafted a whole
bunch of posts only to abandon them later. These last few months of quarantine
and lockdown have been incredibly turbulent and the time slipped by in the
blink of an eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not have much else to report as of now. There are a few things in the
works especially with respect to Tempo and other projects. However, I will be
focusing mainly on my degree for the next while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, study hard and, stay evil.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arming Henchmen: Hacking Guns</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/arming-henchmen-hacking-guns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 15:52:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/arming-henchmen-hacking-guns/</guid>
      <description>I recently watched a video on Wired about a person who found multiple ways to exploit a ‘smart gun’. You can watch that video here.
TL;DR the gun is accompanied by a watch that, when it is close enough to the gun, allows it to shoot. The hacker is able to not only make the gun fire without having the watch nearby, but is also able to jam the signals between the watch and gun and prevent it from firing.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;I recently watched a video on Wired about a person who found multiple ways to
exploit a ‘smart gun’. You can watch that video
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/video/how-a-hacker-fired-a-locked-smart-gun-with-15-of-magnets&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR the gun is accompanied by a watch that, when it is close enough to the
gun, allows it to shoot. The hacker is able to not only make the gun fire
without having the watch nearby, but is also able to jam the signals between
the watch and gun and prevent it from firing. The hacker was also able to
extend the distance the watch has to be for the gun to fire with the use of a
transmitter and repeater. Granted, the hacker investigated the specific
frequencies that the gun and watch used to authenticate and communicate, but
the firing without the watch was done simply using magnets that exploited the
mechanical aspects of the security system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there are a few things I want to touch on here and hopefully I will be able
to frame it within the context of arming the henchmen of my evil corporation.
After all, that is the theme of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, despite its security flaws, I would arm my henchmen with smart guns.
They are already more secure than the regular guns we have today. What the
smart guns do is raise the bar for the gun to be operated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;&amp;hellip; firing without the watch was done &amp;hellip; using magnets that exploited the
mechanical aspects of the security system.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common thing we see nowadays is what I like to call the ‘henchmen ammo supply
chain’ where the hero works their way through a villains compound by
systematically neutralising every minion in their way and taking their weapons
as they go along. Effectively, the hero is given a steady stream of usable
weaponry to help them along. Using smart guns, the hero will be unable to use
the dropped guns, only their ammo. Even then, if the hero isn’t using the exact
same model and calibre gun themselves, they will probably not even be able to
use the ammo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good way to break the hero’s momentum through your evil lair by
ensuring that they run out of resources fairly quickly and are unable to
resupply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps instead of using a smart watch, I would invest in biometric security
for my smart guns such as a fingerprint sensor (&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/wueZubd_S2o&#34;&gt;which has been
developed&lt;/a&gt;).  Given the form factors we can
achieve with our fingerprint sensors on our phones, this seems like a pretty
good idea to do. To push this idea even further, what if the gun was not only
linked to the user’s fingerprint, but also tapped into their entire system
measuring heart rate, brain activity, and so on. That way we could use this
information to not only authenticate, but also possibly map their intent and
use that to decide whether or not the gun will fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;What the smart guns do is raise the bar for the gun to be operated.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, this was an interesting case of a simple workaround to some
seemingly complex security. If your system has a simplistic mechanical bypass
how secure is it really? In the case of smart guns, I would argue they are
still safer than normal, unsecured guns. This comes with the caveat that the
‘smart’ part involves authentication only and not actual fire control. Giving
anyone a way to fire guns remotely/smartly is just a really, really bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bring it back to a real world context, guns are weapons. Like a club or
mace, a gun is not dangerous by itself, but when it is wielded it is capapble
of taking a life. By using smart technology to restrict the operation of a gun
even further, I think we can make guns much safer than they currently are and
also hinder the trade of guns since the authentication is something that will
have to be transferred from seller to buyer. Even though exploits exist, I
would argue that currently, it is much easier for someone to aquire a ‘dumb’
gun and use that than go through the trouble of trying to hack a smart gun.
Inevitably we humans are lazy and will choose the easiest path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’m trying to say is: while the media hype may make it seem like smart
guns with vulnerabilities should not be used, it is in fact the opposite
because they are already safer than normal guns despite their exploits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Let us agree to never ever connect guns to the internet. Ever.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 06:09:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>You might have found yourself here and asked yourself the following questions, “How did I get here? Why am I reading a blog about a malignant enterprise? What is the point of the universe if it’ll end in a massive heat death anyway?”, to which I have the answers (except for the first and last one).</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;You might have found yourself here and asked yourself the following questions,
“How did I get here? Why am I reading a blog about a malignant enterprise? What
is the point of the universe if it’ll end in a massive &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_death_of_the_universe&#34;&gt;heat
death&lt;/a&gt; anyway?”, to
which I have the answers (except for the first and last one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Evil Company Inc is not actually about, say, maiming puppies and enslaving
people, but rather about a subverting the depiction of supervillians in media.
It’s realising that the archetype villian, although misguided and usually
insane, actually contains all the qualities that people today aspire to have
themselves. This is probably a product of my love for V for Vendetta and
Megamind blending together, but hear me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A villain is usually:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;goal driven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dedicated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enthusiastic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hardworking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passionate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tenacious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The villian is highly focused on one specific goal or outcome that they will
stop at nothing to achieve (not even the deafening awesomeness of the hero). It
consumes them and drives them forward. They continually scheme about better
ways to succeed. They also love what they do and enjoy their evil schemes every
step of the way. Despite being soundly beaten time after time by the hero, the
villain will find a way to get back in the game. Villians are also job
creators. They employ hundreds if not thousands of henchmen, minions, and
thugs. Did you ever wonder what happened to Nondescript Thug #42 when the hero
destroyed the villains evil empire?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’m trying to get at is, adopting the nature of an evil villain is not
bad. One way to get there is by accumulating knowledge. I found the following
quote quite fitting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Knowledge is power. Power corrupts. Study hard. Be evil.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nathan Bridges, Mankind&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan, therefore, is to become a supervillian. And like all my supervillian
contemporaries I’ll need to make my plans and schemes known to any heros that
might need something to try and thwart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you can expect to find here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan on posting articles about my experiences in programming, updates and
posts on any games I’m developing, and general other stuff (like my trips if I
go travelling). Check my bio in the sidebar for what I’m interested in as
that’s probably what I’ll post about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of that said, I’d like to welcome you to my evil labratory. I hope
you’ll stick around and see something cool once in a while and that the
shackles aren’t too uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
