<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on Evil Inc.</title>
    <link>http://sudosays.github.io/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on Evil Inc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 15:39:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sudosays.github.io/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 The Diet</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2021-the-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 15:39:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2021-the-diet/</guid>
      <description>Admittedly, the third week in January is a bit late to post my New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution, but better late than never.
Last year, I had a focus on growth with a community slant to it. I donated blood, contributed to an open source project and tried to add to myself.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, the third week in January is a bit late to post my New Year&amp;rsquo;s
Resolution, but better late than never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I had a focus on growth with a community slant to it. I donated
blood, contributed to an open source project and tried to add to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, my central goal is to &amp;ldquo;diet&amp;rdquo;: physically, spiritually, and
digitally. There is a common conception of a diet as a restriction and
reduction of intake, foregoing the things we believe are enjoyable. It leaves
the idea of a diet as a bleak and joyless process that ultimately will end and
we may return to our old habits of eating cake or whatever vice we enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to diet in the holistic sense of the word: to not just reduce/stop
consuming things deemed unhealthy, but to replace them with things that nourish
me. Furthermore, while also physical, I aim to undergo a digital diet as well.
The two overlap on the concept of a &amp;ldquo;dopamine diet&amp;rdquo;, a restriction of excess
neurochemical stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-physical-diet&#34;&gt;The Physical Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is somewhat straightforward: I currently weigh ~82kgs and I would like
that to be under 76kgs. This would shift my BMI from overweight to normal
weight. However, while achieving this, I would like to make it a sustainable
thing and that requires a lifestyle change including diet and exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite sports are surfing, running, and rock climbing. However, due to
the lockdown restrictions and an injury, I am unable to surf or run, which
leaves only climbing. To balance this, I will be adding yoga as a regular
fixture of my routine. The first two weeks of this year, I did yoga almost
every day, and I could definitely feel the benefit it had on not only my
physical well-being, but also helped reduce my stress levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body and the mind are connected. Therefore, an important part of the
physical diet is a practise of managing the psychosomatic response to stress.
Through meditation, yoga, and other mentally restorative practices I hope to
reduce my stress levels. Studies suggest that stress enhances the craving and
increases risk of relapse in alcoholics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for nutrition, I am cutting out all snack and junk foods. The rule is, if it
comes in a sweet packet, or from a fast food restaurant: it is not allowed.
Regular restaurants are a grey area, and so the general rule of thumb is to
take the healthier of the menu options. This is not an absolute rule so that I
can hopefully avoid a self-defeating guilt/binge cycle. The focus is on
rewarding positive change and not punishing failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-digital-diet&#34;&gt;The Digital Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other aspect I would like to tackle is my consumption of digital media.
Whether it be videos, games, social media, or news, I would like to reduce the
amount of digital content I consume. These things are designed to be rewarding,
and some even highly optimised to promote their use/consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest example for me is video games. By design, they reward the player for
completing certain tasks in the game. Furthermore, it is easy to feel a sense
of mastery, accomplishment, or progress especially in games such as Factorio.
For video games, this is an overt part of the design, but for other things such
as social media it is more difficult to spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These systems are designed to be rewarding, to stimulate the release of
dopamine which is linked to our reward centers. The idea is to hijack the
reward stimulus and &amp;ldquo;farm&amp;rdquo; a user for dopamine, increasing engagement. The
problems I have with this is that: a) it can easily become addictive, and b)
overstimulation of the brain can make other tasks feel less rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I realised during lockdown last year, and what I hope to achieve this year
is that I enjoy tackling problems. I thrive when struggling against really
difficult challenges and finding a creative solution for it. Unfortunately, if
my reward centers are already overstimulated, I find it difficult to sink my
teeth into a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therfore, the digital/dopamine diet. Replacing the easy &amp;ldquo;mental junk food&amp;rdquo;
activities with more difficult, but more rewarding activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to replace my current diet of digital entertainment with writing,
reading, meditation, chess, and creative activities such as drawing or
programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-resolution&#34;&gt;The Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above has been very theoretical and wishy washy. The concrete
resolution is as follows (and as always follows the SMART principle):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to lose 6kgs before July 2021 and maintain it until 31 December
2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to reduce my digital consumption to 1 movie or 2 tv episodes
and no more than 1 hour of video games per week by July 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would like to stop consuming any social media and limit the time spent
surfing the internet to 30 minutes per day by the end of the year (31
December 2021).
internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be keeping track of these privately throughout the year and will report
back further.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindsight 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 20:59:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/hindsight-2020/</guid>
      <description>What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost deferred itself.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;What a year this has been. I am sure many are starting their end of the year
posts like this, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate now, it never will be. This year
I set out my goals/resolutions with the theme of growth, specifically I chose
things that were always deferred and, well, if this year was not almost
deferred itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the 5 goals I set, 2 have been completed entirely: contribute to an open
source initiative, and donate blood. These were binary in nature, either I did
them or did not. For the others (yoga/flexibility, writing, and personal
project) it was less clear cut. These goals required continuous and even
effort. As the posts on this blog make clear, the effort was continuous, but
sporadic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did in fact write more, but perhaps it was off target for what I had
envisioned. I also became more flexible, for a while. Finally, I worked on, but
did not complete a personal project. Considering the tumultuous year, I am not
overly disappointed. I made inroads into the goals I had set, and for others I
achieved them. That is enough for me and enough about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year will definitely be one for the history books. Wracked by a pandemic,
society was torn apart and recombined. As the virus swept around the globe,
countries went into various stages of lockdown. South Africa, for one went into
a total lock down for a long time before a phased return to a new normal. Even
now, 2021 is gearing up for another year of pandemic protocols and social
upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout all of this, we have been given the display of the best of humanity
and the worst of humanity. Though separated through social distancing, we
connected through the internet. We drew closer together to immediate family. We
took, hopefully, a step back and noted the things we missed, and those we could
probably live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, the economic and social devastation has not even begun to rear its
ugly head. The bell has tolled ceaselessly and will continue to do so. By all
indications, this virus is here to stay for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the metaphorical night will grow ever darker over the next few years, but
hopefully we can remain huddled around a flicker of light, together.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, August 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-august-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 15:32:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-august-2020/</guid>
      <description>Yet again it is time for another update. The past month I have been incredibly busy. I have recently taken up a lecturing position for a Java course at a local university. While entirely online/remote, the work is quite time consuming if not overly difficult. I have found it interesting to develop an effective workflow and schedule, and to find the relevant tools that allow me to do so.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;Yet again it is time for another update. The past month I have been incredibly
busy. I have recently taken up a lecturing position for a Java course at a
local university. While entirely online/remote, the work is quite time
consuming if not overly difficult. I have found it interesting to develop an
effective workflow and schedule, and to find the relevant tools that allow me
to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested, my current &amp;ldquo;stack&amp;rdquo;/workflow for lectures is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing all slides and notes in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiling to Beamer slides with &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org/&#34;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording of lecture videos material with &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/&#34;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://junit.org/junit5/&#34;&gt;JUnit 5&lt;/a&gt; for automated assignment marking and testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sakailms.org/&#34;&gt;Sakai&lt;/a&gt; for student interaction and assessments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also found myself using &lt;a href=&#34;https://taskwarrior.org/&#34;&gt;Taskwarrior&lt;/a&gt; quite a
bit, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I really like it. Something about the usage seems to
rub at me. For a while I was considering adding Taskwarrior support to Tempo,
but I will probably hold off for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I am currently preparing a paper for the SACAIR conference as
part of my MSc work. It is proving an intense process, but I expected it would
be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what free time I have left, I find myself surfing, playing chess, and
playing Bloodborne (although not that often).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself itching to work on Tempo as well as a plethora of other personal
project ideas (mostly in Go). For now though, they will have to remain on the
backburner. Until the next update, keep well in these interesting times.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, July 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:41:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>It is time again for me to fill you in with another status update. I have been incredibly busy with my academics this past while which has left little time for side-projects (despite how much I would like to work on them). What little time I have free I have been surfing, meditating, doing yoga, and sleeping to try and recover and recoup.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;It is time again for me to fill you in with another status update. I have been
incredibly busy with my academics this past while which has left little time
for side-projects (despite how much I would like to work on them). What little
time I have free I have been surfing, meditating, doing yoga, and sleeping to
try and recover and recoup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of what my workload looks like I mapped it with
Matplotlib+Numpy using &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/32485907/matplotlib-and-numpy-create-a-calendar-heatmap&#34;&gt;Joe
Kinton&amp;rsquo;s
answer&lt;/a&gt;
on Stack Overflow as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/workload_heatmap.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/workload_heatmap.png&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My productivity app Tempo has seen some slight changes as I have tinkered away
at it and I have been using it relentlessly to keep myself focused and maintain
my work momentum. A lot has been changed and improved since the last devlog and
frankly another one is long overdue. Yet again, I have found that using my app
constantly really brings to light any issues or quirks that annoy me which has
been a great way to know what things I need to change or polish first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have been writing more Go in my spare time &amp;mdash; mostly with toy
projects &amp;mdash; and I have to say that I am quickly falling in love with it. I had
expected my self to prefer Rust, but somehow Go pleasantly surprised me with
the dev tools. In some way I feel that Go has been a lot easier for me to grok
than Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That does not mean that I have abandoned learning Rust, but rather
that I have shelved it for now in favour of focusing on mastering Go. I am
still especially interested in adding Rust to my repertoire especially since
there is talk of including &lt;a href=&#34;https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CAKwvOdmuYc8rW_H4aQG4DsJzho=F+djd68fp7mzmBp3-wY--Uw@mail.gmail.com/T/#u&#34;&gt;in-tree Rust
support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update, June 2020</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 17:34:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/status-update-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>This post is inspired by the status updates of Drew DeVault (who remains a large inspiration for keeping this blog as a whole). This entry is a bit late, but better than never. In future I think I will also try to update at the middle of each month. This is also a chance to add updates from my life that do not warrant a full post here or may seem unrelated to the spirit of this blog.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by the status updates of Drew DeVault (who remains a
large inspiration for keeping this blog as a whole). This entry is a bit late,
but better than never. In future I think I will also try to update at the
middle of each month. This is also a chance to add updates from my life that do
not warrant a full post here or may seem unrelated to the spirit of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last post to this blog was &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/blog/be-static-to-go-faster/&#34;&gt;Be Static To Go Faster&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which dates back to the 25th of February
this year. In the intervening months, many, many things have happened. I have
been working towards the completion of my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree, drafted a whole
bunch of posts only to abandon them later. These last few months of quarantine
and lockdown have been incredibly turbulent and the time slipped by in the
blink of an eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not have much else to report as of now. There are a few things in the
works especially with respect to Tempo and other projects. However, I will be
focusing mainly on my degree for the next while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, study hard and, stay evil.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Vision</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2020-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 19:56:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/2020-vision/</guid>
      <description>While normally I would keep my New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions to myself, blogging more is one of them. If I could control how this year will turn out for me I would summarise it in one word: growth. My aim this year is to extend myself in as many aspects as I can while ensuring lasting impact.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;While normally I would keep my New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions to myself, blogging more
is one of them. If I could control how this year will turn out for me I would
summarise it in one word: growth. My aim this year is to extend myself in as
many aspects as I can while ensuring lasting impact. As such, I have narrowed
it down to five resolutions or goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all of these conform to the S.M.A.R.T principle of goal setting, but I
don&amp;rsquo;t think resolutions have to be such hard goals. Regardless, they are as
follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to an open source initiative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donate blood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become more flexible (with yoga)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write more (in this blog and elsewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete a personal project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had trouble deciding on which ones exactly to include here, but I think these
represent things that I had always told myself I would get around to at some
point. They represent deferred, delayed, and abandoned ideas/goals that I think
make them prime candidates for this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the growth I seek is commitment: building on things that I believe
will make me a better, more dedicated person while contributing to my community
(online or otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these, I have included a brief on how I imagined they would be
accomplished or how I envisioned them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source initiatives to contribute to include Wikipedia, and Rust-based
projects for helping me learn the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donating blood is pretty self-explanatory, I am ashamed to say I have never
really done it before and it has always been a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming more flexible is a physical challenge I set myself since I recovered
from my advanced shin splints. Lack of flexibility in my hamstrings was one of
the leading factors to the development of what could have been a chronic
injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing more involves building out this blog and taking the initiative to share
my knowledge and personal discoveries with others. Blogs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://drewdevault.com/&#34;&gt;Drew
DeVault&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; are a big source of inspiration for this
one. I also have many other writing projects that have simply never been a
priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I want to see a personal project through to completion. My project
graveyard stretches across the horizon while my harvest remains empty. I hope
to start adding to the archive and showcase of this blog at least one project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to challenge you &amp;mdash; dear reader &amp;mdash; to anything this year it would
be this: find something you have always deferred and just start the work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UltraTrail 2019</title>
      <link>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/ultratrail-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 18:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sudosays.github.io/blog/ultratrail-2019/</guid>
      <description>On the 30th of November this year I ran the 35km Ultra Trail in Cape Town.
At a glance, it took me a total of 8 hours 15 minutes to complete with an average pace of 13:53 min/km. According to my running watch, I burned 4583 calories with an average heart rate of 156bpm and a max heart rate of 186bpm over the entire 8+ hours.</description>
      <content>
        &lt;p&gt;On the 30th of November this year I ran the 35km Ultra Trail in Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a glance, it took me a total of 8 hours 15 minutes to complete with an
average pace of 13:53 min/km. According to my running watch, I burned 4583
calories with an average heart rate of 156bpm and a max heart rate of 186bpm
over the entire 8+ hours. At a rough estimate, I drank 3.7 litres of water with
the heaviest consumption occurring between the 14km and 24km aid stations where
I completely drained my 1.5l race pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the official race timings and stats &lt;a href=&#34;https://utct.livetrail.run/coureur.php?rech=1572&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date this is my longest (time and distance) singular race event ever and I
thought I would share my experience and reflect on it. As such this post may
get a bit rambly and lengthy, but I have interspersed some photos of the event
to keep you interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_001.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_001.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;View of Cape Town from the Platteklip Gorge.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;View of Cape Town from the Platteklip Gorge.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to buy an entry in April this year and opted for the 35km over the
21km largely due to two factors: I wanted to push myself, and the 21km featured
a single climb over the saddle between Devil&amp;rsquo;s Peak and Table Mountain that
seemed quite dangerous to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, I ran my first half-marathon in Meiringspoort and I was confident I
could run 21km comfortably and wanted to push out past my comfort zone and
extend myself. Also, the 35km offered a traversal of Table Mountain and I
thought it was a great excuse to have an extended day on top of the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had my entry it came time for the training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_002.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_002.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;View of Platteklip Gorge during the ascent.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;View of Platteklip Gorge during the ascent.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year I saw a physio for some pretty advanced shin splints and
started a cross-training program with additional rehabilitation exercises.
Since the cross-training required cycling, I took up spinning and soon after
decided to commit to full triathlon training for an Olympic distance triathlon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the triathlon training to be super effective and enjoyable. It did
involve a lot more  cycling and swimming than running, but that was perfectly
fine since I was not supposed to be running so much in any case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The months flew by until roughly mid September when I got sick (likely from a
combination of overtraining, poor nutrition, and stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_003.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_003.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;View of Devil&amp;amp;rsquo;s Peak from the top of Table Mountain.&#34; height=&#34;450px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;View of Devil&amp;rsquo;s Peak from the top of Table Mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good two weeks lost and a whole bunch of fitness and muscle tone down
the drain, I managed to recover and restart training just in time for the
Meiringspoort half-marathon on the 12th of October. I surprised myself with a
finish time of 1:51:44 (only 4 minutes slower than last year&amp;rsquo;s 1:47:10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as race-day neared I became ever more encumbered by my work and
the priority of training dropped. As a result, I had not yet scouted the route,
broken in my trail shoes, done proper hill training, or run technical trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say I was nervous is an understatement. However, quitting and abandoning
this event was never really an option for me. Instead, I decided I would just
enjoy it as much as possible without worrying too much about setting a record
time or not. I set myself two core rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would run easy and slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would stop to take pictures and enjoy the scenes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back now, I am grateful I reframed it as I did. It really helped shift
my mentality to one of enjoyment in the undertaking and I would like to think,
contributed greatly to my overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_005.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_005.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Start of the descent down Nursery Ravine.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Start of the descent down Nursery Ravine.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on to actual the actual race. I was expecting a total time of roughly 10
hours, but I failed to take into account how congested the route would be. I
did indeed run when I was able to, but rather because the rest of the time I
would be hiking behind other racers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chokepoints of the route were Platteklip Gorge (and most of the beginning),
between Maclear&amp;rsquo;s Beacon and just before the aid station, and the Newland&amp;rsquo;s
Forest stairs. Once I had passed the stairs, the field opened up considerably,
but by that point my muscles were very heavily fatigued and made running
difficult to maintain for any considerable amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember at a point after the climb to the King&amp;rsquo;s Blockhouse I could only maintain
a run for at most 2-3 minutes before resorting to a fast walk. During most of
the race after Nursery Ravine, I remember repeating a little mantra to myself
that &amp;ldquo;run when you can, walk when you can&amp;rsquo;t run, but always stay moving
forward&amp;rdquo; over and over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_006.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_006.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;During the descent of Nursery Ravine.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;During the descent of Nursery Ravine.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that really stuck with me was how quickly time passed. I thought that
this will be an extended grind with gnashing of teeth and pain, but the first
14km or so passed by really quickly. I definitely experienced a sustained flow
state during the event with even the muscle pain not hampering my performance
too much. It could be that or it could have been the cramp block tablets I took
that I am sure saved my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself struggling to form a coherent narrative for this post and so
thought I would just rattle off a view highlights and notable events instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather on the day was as good as could be bargained for. Cool and cloudy
in the morning for the climb up Platteklip, and not windy for the homeward
stretch around Devil&amp;rsquo;s Peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the ascent of Platteklip, there was a bagpiper a little more than
halfway up. At the end of every tune, everyone would cheer and clap, and the
piper would take up another song. With the cloud rolling over the top of the
gorge it really lent a special air to the whole scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_008.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sudosays.github.io/imgs/utct2019/utct_008.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Climb to the King&amp;amp;rsquo;s Blockhouse.&#34; height=&#34;550px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Climb to the King&amp;rsquo;s Blockhouse.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views of Constantia and False Bay from Maclear&amp;rsquo;s Beacon were truly
breathtaking. At one point, I could see both sides of the Cape Penninsula before
me. It was just after this that I was able to help out a fellow racer by
offering some of my cramp block tablets. There was a prevailing spirit of
camaraderie and people were quick to help one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aid stations were excellently stocked with snacks and drinks. In
particular, at the aid station by UCT I managed to snag a Red Bull and some
jelly babies as well as seeing my supporters. After the 24km it took to get
there, seeing my loved ones there really made the last 10km bearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to finish strong with a run, and the macaroni and cheese afterwards
tasted like victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of aftermath, I was surprised at how quickly I managed to recover and
how I sustained no lasting damage. That being said, this event worked every
muscle in my legs. Trail running, it turns out, is a very comprehensive leg
exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All things considered, I am proud of what I accomplished with this event. I did
what I set out to do months ago, and even exceeded my own expectations. I am
still a bit uncertain if I would end up doing it next year, but I do know that
I will be doing more trail running regardless.&lt;/p&gt;

      </content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
